Daniel Precioso

daniprec.github.io | LinkedIn | GitHub | ResearchGate

Location: Madrid, Spain Email: <u>daniel.precioso@uca.es</u> ORCID: 0000-0003-3836-1429

DATA SCIENTIST

I am a highly skilled data scientist with over **5 years of experience** in **machine learning** and **Python**. With a passion for learning and growth, I am a highly motivated and proactive individual who enjoys working collaboratively to solve complex problems. My strong team work skills and ability to communicate effectively enable me to contribute to successful project outcomes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Python, Matlab, R

Libraries : NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, TensorFlow

Dev Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Github

Academic Tools: Latex

EXPERIENCE

Lead Data ScientistApr 2023 – PresentCanonical GreenMadrid, Spain

• Development of data science solutions for ecological transition in the maritime industry.

• Proficient in delivering persuasive commercial and technical presentations.

Data ScientistKomorebi Al
Madrid, Spain

- Data cleaning, manipulation and visualization.
- Design, train and deployment of machine learning and deep learning models with scikit-learn, including GB and CNN.
- Development of a dashboard to guide industrial decision making with Streamlit.

Predoctoral Research Staff

University of Cádiz

Sep 2019 – Aug 2022

Cádiz, Spain

- Collaboration with various industrial partners to conduct cutting-edge research in healthcare, energy and blue economy.
- Presentation of research findings to both technical and non-technical audiences.
- Publication of research papers in peer-reviewed journals.

Junior Data Scientist

Jan 2019 – Jun 2019

Foqum Madrid, Spain

EDUCATION

Phd in Data Science University of Cádiz	Sep 2019 – Jul 2023 <i>Cádiz, Spain</i>
MSc in Statistical and Computational Information Processing Universidad Politécnica de Madrid	Sep 2018 – Jul 2019 <i>Madrid, Spain</i>
Degree in Physics Complutense University of Madrid	Sep 2014 – Jul 2018 <i>Madrid, Spain</i>

NeoCam

Machine learning, Python

Univesidad de Cádiz

- We used the Luxonis OAK-D smart camera to build a contactless monitoring system for newborn babies.
- The proposed solution combined computer vision, machine learning, edge computing, cloud computing and Internet of things.
- NeoCam project was awarded the second prize in the international final of <u>OpenCV AI Competition 2021</u>, in which over 1400 teams participated.

Smart Shipping

Data science, Python

Univesidad de Cádiz

- Our goal was to optimize marine shipping routes, by using real time information of ocean currents, wind and waves.
- Smart Shipping project was awarded the second prize in the international final of Ocean Hackathon 2021, hosted by Campus Mondiale de la Mer in Brest (France).

UCAnFly Physics, Matlab Univesidad de Cádiz

- We designed an nanosatellite to test emerging technologies for space-based gravitational wave detectors, such as LISA.
- UCAnFly was led by a multidisciplinary team at the University of Cádiz, with the support of the Education Office of the European Space Agency, under the educational <u>Fly Your Satellite!</u> programme.

ATENEA Data science, Python Univesidad de Cádiz

- This project was hosted by Airbus D&S with financial support from the CDTI Interconnecta program.
- The aim was to introduce machine learning and natural language processing to streamline certain manufacturing processes in Airbus D&S production plants.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine learning in Python with scikit-learn (France Université Numérique)
- XV Modeling Week at UCM (Coordinator) (UCM)
- Fly your Satellite 3 CDR Virtual Workshop (ESA)
- TensorFlow in Practice Specialization (Coursera)
- Applied Social Network Analysis in Python (Coursera)
- Applied Machine Learning in Python (Coursera)
- Applied Text Mining in Python (Coursera)
- Introduction to Data Science in Python (Coursera)

PUBLICATIONS

- · How do tuna schools associate to dFADs? A study using echo-sounder buoys to identify global patterns
- NeoCam: An edge-cloud platform for non-invasive real-time monitoring in neonatal intensive care units
- TUN-AI: Tuna biomass estimation with Machine Learning models trained on oceanography and echosounder FAD data
- Effectiveness of non-pharmaceutical interventions in nine fields of activity to decrease SARS-CoV-2 transmission (Spain, September 2020-May 2021)
- Thresholding Methods in Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring